Peyton Rous Papers 1909-1970 Mss.B.R77
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, ca.1917-1970; 47.0 Linear feet (Box 1-85)
  - Willcox Research Inst., Inc.
  - Williams, Charles M
  - Williams, George
  - Williams, Greer
  - Williams, Linsly R
  - Williams, Robert P.
  - Williams, Roger J
  - Williams, William Frederic
  - Wilson, George
  - Wilson, George W
  - Wilson, Julius L
  - Wilson, Thomas J
    - Grimes, Johanna
    - Moe, Henry Allen
  - Winfrey, R P
  - Wingate, Allan
  - Winlock, Herbert E
  - Winning, Stuart A
  - Winslow, C.-E. A
  - Winternitz, M C
  - Winters, Alexander J
  - Winters, Pamela
  - Wiseman, A
  - Wislocki, George B
  - Wissler, Robert W
  - Withering Lectures
    - Barnes, Stanley
    - Burton, C G
  - Wittmann, W
  - Woglom, William H
  - Woglom, Mrs. William H
  - Wohl, Sonia
  - Wolbach, S Burt
    - Miller, C Philip
    - Hertig, Arthur T
  - Wolbach. Illustrations for talk at the Academy, December 16, 1937
  - Wolcott, Mark W
  - Wolf, Ava
  - Wolf, Julius
  - Wolfe, J M
  - Wolferth, Charles
  - Wolfle, Dale
  - Wollstein, Martha
  - Womack, Charles
  - Wood, David A
  - Wood, Francis C
  - Wood, Mrs. Frank P
    - Black, James Harvey
    - Shelmire, Jesse B
    - Wood, Frank P
  - Wood, W Barry, Jr.
  - Woodbridge, Louise
  - Woodruff, Lorande L
  - Woods, Alan C
  - Woods, Hiram
  - Woodward, William T
  - Woolley, D W
  - Worcester, J L
  - World Biography
  - World Health Organization
  - Wormall, A
  - Wortis, S Bernard
  - Wright, Arthur
  - Wright, Helen
  - Wright, J E
  - Wright, V W Murray
  - Wrinch, D J
  - Wu, Henry
  - Wu, S D
  - Wuest, Margaret
  - Wyckoff, Ralph W G
  - Wyeth, George Austin
    - Claude, Albert
  - Wyeth, Mrs. Margaret C
  - Wynder, N
  - Wyss, Edouard
    - DuBois, Eugene F
  - Yadin, Yigael
  - Yaharees, Herbert C., Jr.
  - Yale Scientific Magazine
  - Yale University
  - Yale University Press
  - Yamagiwa, K
  - Yates, J L
  - Yellin, H
  - Yoshida, Tomizo
  - Young, Hugh H
  - Young, J S
  - Young, Mahonri Sharp
  - Yourga, Frank J
  - Yun, I S
  - Zabary-Simon, P
    - Rivers, Thomas M
  - Zauderer, George, & Sons
  - Zehner, Harry
  - Zeidman, Irving
  - Zeisler, Erwin Paul
  - Zepp, C P
  - Zifferblatt, A H
  - Zigrosser, Carl
  - Zilber, L A
  - Zingher, Mrs. Abraham
  - Zinsser, Hans
    - Flexner, Simon
    - Rivers, Thomas M
    - Seastone, C V., Jr.
  - Zionist Archives and Library
  - Zondek, Bernhard
  - Zoning
  - Zozaya, Jose
    - Tenbroeck, Carl
  - Zuccala, George S
  - Zumoff, Barnett
  - Zweifach, Benjamin W
  - _____ Magdalen
- Series II. Oswald H. Robertson Material, 1917-1960; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 85-86)
  Professional and personal correspondence between Peyton Rous and his friend and colleague, Oswald H. Robertson. Included in the series is some valuable correspondence regarding the use of preserved blood and blood banks during the First World War, and discussions of later research by Robertson and Rous at the Rockefeller Institute. Also, there is a group of the scientific papers of Dr. Robertson. Presented by Dr. Peyton Rous; April 1969. 1969 756ms. Unless otherwise stated, the letters are to or from Dr. Robertson.
  - Award of the Kober medal to Peyton Rouse (also, materials used by Dr. Robertson for the talk), 1953
  - China memorabilia of O.H.Robertson.
  - Correspondence with Robertson, 1917-1960
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1917 June 27; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Simon Flexner, 1917 prior to Oct. 7; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1917 Oct. 11; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1917 Oct. 12; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1917 Oct. 18; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1917 Dec. 10; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1917 Dec. 29; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1918 Feb. 1; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1918 Feb. 4; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1918 March 8; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1918 March 24; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1918 May 29; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1918 Aug. 27; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1918 Nov. 4; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1918 Nov. 28; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1918 Dec. 13; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1922 Aug. 17; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1923 Aug. 8; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1923 Dec. 1; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1924 Feb. 21; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1924 Dec. 3; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1925 Feb. 28; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1925 May 8; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1926 Jan. 3; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1926 April 13; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1928 Jan. 20; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1928 Jan. 24; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1929 Nov. 6; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1929 Dec. 18; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1929 Dec. 28; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1930 April 22; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1930 Oct. 1; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1931 April 21; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1931 May 25; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1933 April 29; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1933 May 2; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1934 Nov. 26; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1934 Dec. 18; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1934 Dec. 20; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1935 Jan. 3; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1935 May 1; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1936 April 17; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1936 Aug. 18; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1936 Aug. 23; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1936 Aug. 28; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1936 Dec. 5; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1937 May 11; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1938 March 11; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1938 March 15; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1938 May 9; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1938 May 12; Rous, Peyton
    - from, to J.C.Furnas, 1938 May 13
    - from, to J.C.Furnas, 1938 May 16
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1939 Oct. 6; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1939 Oct. 18; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1939 Oct. 30; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1939 Nov. 9; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1939 Nov. 15; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1939 Dec. 5; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1940 Feb. 21; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1940 Feb. 26; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1940 March 8; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1940 April 29; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1940 April 30; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1941 April 1; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1941 April 4; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1941 June 4; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1941 Nov. 16; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1941 Nov. 24; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1941 Nov. 26; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1942 Nov. 4; Rous, Peyton
    - (to and from Hans T. Clarke and P.Rouse, In re. O.H.Robertson dinner.), 1943 April 5, 7, 9
    - to - telegram, 1944 May 9
    - from - telegram, 1944 May 9
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1944 Nov. 14; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1944 Nov. 21; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1944 Dec. 11; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1948 Aug. 19; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1948 Oct. 18; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1948 Oct. 22; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1948 Oct. 26; Rous, Peyton
    - from, 1948 Nov. 3 1948
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1948 Nov. 9; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1949 June 18; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1949 June 20; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1949 Dec. 17; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1951 Nov. 7; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1952 April 9; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1952 April 24; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1952 May 5; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1952 June 13; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1952 Nov. 2; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1952 Dec. 7; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1953 Jan. 8; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1953 Jan. 22; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1953 Jan. 26; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1953 Feb. 10; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Oswald H. Robertson, 1953 Feb. 17; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1953 April 4; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1953 April 19; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Herbert R. Brown, Jr., 1953 April 30; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1953 May 16; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1953 June 8; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1953 Aug. 5; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1953 Oct. 1; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1957 Aug. 19; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1958 March 19; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1958 April 4; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1958 Nov. 13; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1958 Dec. 5; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - 1958 Dec. 15, Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to P. L. Mollison (in re. Oswald H. Robertson), 1958 Dec. 15; Rous, Peyton
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1959 Feb. 12; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1959 May 1; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1959 May 9; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1959 Sept. 29; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1960 Aug. 14; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
    - Letter to Peyton Rous, 1960 Oct. 3; Robertson, O. H. (Oswald Hope), 1886-1966
  - Photograph and glass negative (broken)
  - Photographs of fish, regrouped for Rous' lantern slide for Kober medal lecture
  - Publications of O.. Robertson, ca.1930
    Bibliography
  - Watson, C.J., to P.Rous in re O. H.Robertson 1960 Aug. 12, and reply, 1960 Aug. 18
  - "Presentation of the Kober Medal 1961 to O. H. Robertson." [and] "Acceptance" by O. H. Robertson. [printed], Rous, Peyton
  - Preservation of living red blood cells in vitro (used by O.H.Robertson in 1918), 2 copies; Rous, Peyton and Turner, J. R.
- Series III. Card files and Miscellaneous, 1909-ca.1950s; 12.0 Linear feet (Box 86-111)
  The card files include several thousand 4 by 6" cards bearing laboratory records, chiefly concerning experiments on domestic rabbit (DR), but also some bibliographic card files. At the end of the series are three bound volumes.
  - Card files on domestic rabbit experiments, bibliographies, etc., 26 boxes, 12 lin. feet; Rous, Peyton
  - Rous Family account book, 1909-1920; 1 vol.; Rous, Peyton
  - "Book of ideas", before 1918; 1 vol.; Rous, Peyton
  - Investment record, 1931-1935; 1 vol.; Rous, Peyton
- Photographs, Photographs from Peyton Rous papers. Many photographs were seperated from this collection and stored in the "Print Collection."
  - Albert Baird Hastings, bust, formal, n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); 3/4 view formal bust portrait of Hastings.
  - Formal protrait of P. A. Deveau [?], 1925; 1.0 Photograph(s); Formal portrait, 3/4 view, of man with mustache.